# **Max Lewis**

Aspiring Software Engineer looking to learn and create impact.

Lockport, Illinois, US | +1 (815) 708-4410 | mlew3223@gmail.com

https://github.com/mslew | https://www.linkedin.com/in/maximuslewis/ | https://www.maxlewis.dev/

# **Computer Science Graduate**

I am a recent computer science graduate with substantial hands-on experience with Python, Java, JavaScript, and Full Stack development. Perceptive problem solver with an innate ability to learn quickly and apply previous experience with original solutions to solve problems.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor of Science, Computer Science, Lewis University**

May 2023

- GPA: 3.82/4.0, magna cum laude
- Dean's List: all four years.
- Outstanding Student Employee of the ECaMS Department for the 2022-2023 school year.
- Dr. Stephany Schlachter Excellence in Undergraduate Scholarship Award Finalist.
- Schmidt Family Foundation Grant for Academic Excellence 2020-2023.

#### **SKILLS**

**Programming Languages**: Java (Proficient), Python (Proficient), JavaScript (Proficient), SQL (Proficient), HTML (Proficient), CSS (Proficient), Go (Familiar)

Technologies: React, Node.js, Express.js, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap 5, Sass, Svelte, Microsoft Azure, Google Firebase

#### **PROJECTS**

### QuizMaster | https://github.com/QuizMasterInc/QuizMaster

Jan. 2023 - May 2023

- Designed, as part of an Agile Scrum team, a comprehensive quizzing application to keep users' minds sharp on various topics.
- Redesigned and modernized the front-end application from HTML/CSS/JavaScript to React and Tailwind CSS
  optimizing the user experience.
- Onboarded and mentored Juniors to develop new features and take over maintenance ensuring project continuity.

# In Theaters | https://github.com/mslew/in-theaters

Oct. 2022 - Dec. 2022

- Built an Android application, in Java, that allows users to see new movies in theaters that week.
- Integrated Google services for ticket purchases, providing a holistic ticket-buying experience.

#### An Agent-Based Model of Clostridioides difficile in Healthcare Settings

June 2022 - May 2023

- Lead a team for the development of an agent-based model built with NetLogo
- Tracks infections of Clostridioides difficile due to environmental conditions in a healthcare setting.
- Forthcoming publication in the Journal of Mathematical Biology, 2024.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Building Custodian, Will County School District 92**

Aug. 2018 - Present

- Maintained building cleanliness per district standards for an assigned 8 classrooms.
- Collaborated with staff members to establish well-running classes and school events.

### **ECaMS Tutor, Lewis University**

Aug. 2022 - May 2023

- Advised students in Computer Science and Mathematics.
- Collaborated with professors and tutors to better aid students.

## **AWARDS AND ACCOLADES**

MAA Mathfest – Janet L. Andersen Award for Outstanding Undergraduate Research

2022

• The Annual Meeting of the Illinois Section of the MAA – Outstanding Undergraduate Research

2023